[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ac", "question": "Which city was the first to own a subway system?", "answer": "London", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92a", "question": "What nationality was Dr. James Naismith, the inventor of basketball?", "answer": "Canadian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5921fd86a4edfd43a087adca", "question": "What can be styled in a \"Half-Windsor\" or a \"Hanover\"?", "answer": "A tie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339833", "question": "What movie, set in Vietnam, won an Oscar for \"Best Picture\" in 1987?", "answer": "Platoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b68406d333868d34d6f2", "question": "Which British royal family changed its name from Saxe-Coburg-Gotha in 1917?", "answer": "Windsors", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac90", "question": "Which US robbers had the surnames Parker and Barrow?", "answer": "Bonnie and Clyde", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ce", "question": "Which Mario Kart game first featured 12 racers instead of 8?", "answer": "Mario Kart Wii", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339156", "question": "Who said: \"We are more popular than Jesus\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590679b0ff9c0647b50a8050", "question": "On January 1, 2016, which Canadian province became the first one to allow the testing of self-driving vehicles on public roads?", "answer": "Ontario", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969c", "question": "Who played Jason's love interest in the 2002 movie \"The Bourne Identity\"?", "answer": "Franka Potente", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8cc8494b094db915830a0", "question": "Which 2016 film received Titanic-equivalent 14 Academy Award nominations?", "answer": "La La Land", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63a", "question": "Which bird lays the largest eggs?", "answer": "Ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab0b36baab681b09292166", "question": "Who was the first king of Jerusalem?", "answer": "King Saul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c3b49076251badbead0", "question": "Which First Lady was the first to graduate college?", "answer": "Lucy Hayes -- The wife of President Rutherford B. Hayes, she received her degree from Wesleyan Female College at the age of 18.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7ff9d13a3a814d89068c58", "question": "What unit of measurement is approximately 100 fathoms?", "answer": "A Cable", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5d", "question": "What is the only US state to boast a radio station whose call letters are the exact same name of the city?", "answer": "Waco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca9", "question": "In what century did Leonardo Da Vinci paint the \"Mona Lisa\"?", "answer": "16th Century", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54c", "question": "\"Consumption\" was the former name of what disease?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e3f3965cb9e8bda6821364", "question": "When was the Rosetta Stone found?", "answer": "1799", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc3", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by The Thompson Twins?", "answer": "Doctor! Doctor!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ff9513a3a814d89068c53", "question": "What is Ethiopia's official language?", "answer": "Amharic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597ddf7677980686f722d187", "question": "What city was host to the first official Association football game in 1863?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd9", "question": "What TV show did \"Top of the Heap\" spin off from?", "answer": "Married...with Children", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd2", "question": "In biblical etiology, which animal became extinct because it was thrown off the ark and drowned?", "answer": "The unicorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b012", "question": "Which of the continental US states was the last to be admitted to the Union?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe0da95fcbed638185eaa06", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s highest inhabited city?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a36a", "question": "What country is Transilvania in?", "answer": "Romania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e804ffde59ea584496fea8", "question": "Archie Moore is typically associated with which sport?", "answer": "Boxing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbd", "question": "What model was married to musician Travis Barker?", "answer": "Shanna Moakler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08a", "question": "Who kept searching for his long lost salt shaker?", "answer": "Jimmy Buffett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bb357722627b8fe95581be4", "question": "Brisbane is the capital of which Australian state?", "answer": "Queensland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d7", "question": "Antarctica is surrounded by which ocean?", "answer": "Southern ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b507", "question": "What is tripe on a menu?", "answer": "Stomach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59524338736d4be723796b67", "question": "How many of the same item can you get in the term \"Bakers Dozen\"?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c88ea0222f44c2d77a29c4a", "question": "Where was the International Monetary Fund founded in 1944?", "answer": "The Bretton Woods Conference", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e147775dd42e4a67cb8d3ea", "question": "What is the name of Weird Al Yankovic's 1989 feature film?", "answer": "UHF", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358dba5db0d66a186cb563", "question": "If a chemical is \"anhydrous\", what does it not contain?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338918", "question": "Who became the first person to become a billionaire by writing books?", "answer": "J.K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5cd40e06685cf15b733e9896", "question": "In fencing what is the name of the action when two fencers make physical contact with any part of their bodies (or hilts)?", "answer": "Corps-a-corps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd7", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"rodeo\"?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b32368ebf195a31e15d73bc", "question": "An \"omniscient\" person has unlimited what?", "answer": "Knowledge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac89", "question": "How were Theodore and Franklin Roosevelt related?", "answer": "They were fifth cousins", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc86", "question": "What color is the one-ball in a traditional billiards set?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9381f6bd93ce3a4e5f67e", "question": "Hippopotomonstrosesquipedaliophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Long words", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b5c901dd7bf43be5e7d5", "question": "What sporting event is referred to as \"The Run for the Roses\"?", "answer": "Kentucky Derby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7357feec85e375820b24c", "question": "Who said, \"Personally I\u2019m always ready to learn, although I do not always like being taught.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596dfc6d9616e6c6d4eba4f1", "question": "Betsy Ross was born with a fully formed set of what?", "answer": "Teeth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b358c035db0d66a186cb55a", "question": "The \"Arenga Micrantha\" species of flowering plants is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "The Tibetan sugar palm", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad53", "question": "Who was the first woman to be entombed at the Pantheon on her own merit?", "answer": "Marie Curie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c516", "question": "How many stars are in the Big Dipper constellation?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a48", "question": "In the TV series, which one of the four main characters on \"Sex and the City\" had a baby?", "answer": "Miranda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a728c4c6bcd28c119383284", "question": "What reference book went on sale for the first time in 1955?", "answer": "The Guinness Book of Records", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede0c96ce05a3942286dbb", "question": "What horror film featured the character Samara Morgan?", "answer": "\"The Ring\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133991f", "question": "What was the name of the first spin-off from the TV show \"Law & Order\"?", "answer": "Law & Order: SVU", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f95b00855722f97b22684da", "question": "In the \"Harry Potter\" universe, who dies during the third Tri-wizard Tournament?", "answer": "Cedric Diggory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c9", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"I've said it before and I'll say it again: Democracy simply doesn't work.\"?", "answer": "Kent Brockman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c946", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for krypton?", "answer": "Kr", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad4a", "question": "Gangster Al Capone was eventually arrested and convicted on what charge?", "answer": "Tax evasion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b1", "question": "Quito is the capital of which South American country?", "answer": "Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecd2a0ec223966ae8f88c5", "question": "In \"The Wolf of Wall Street\", what did the actors snort in scenes that involved cocaine?", "answer": "Vitamin B", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec26578dc25ca9e12ef64a", "question": "How many millimeters are in an inch?", "answer": "25.4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a0a06c0f9723ab15cb36", "question": "What was the inspiration behind a 12-person jury?", "answer": "The 12 Apostles of Jesus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab09", "question": "What is the capital of the Tonga?", "answer": "Nuku'alofa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b045", "question": "When did the American Revolutionary War start?", "answer": "1775", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf3", "question": "What continent is Kyrgystan located in?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aafd", "question": "The Volta is the largest river in which country?", "answer": "Ghana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feb58407e83c707845b20cd", "question": "The Halloween practice of an individual's pocket that has been turned inside out and left to dangle, is aimed at protecting the individual from which hungry creatures?", "answer": "Owls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945b", "question": "Who does David Paymer play in the 1995 movie \"Get Shorty\"?", "answer": "Shorty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a275", "question": "What democratic senator that is a cousin of actress/comedian Amy Schumer?", "answer": "Charles \"Chuck\" Schumer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c496", "question": "How many throwing events are there in a decathlon?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d46", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Heaven\"?", "answer": "Cate Blanchett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69e5120565ad31a57c781", "question": "\"Night of Broken Glass\" was also called what?", "answer": "Kristallnacht", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c0", "question": "What bird is New Zealand's national symbol?", "answer": "The Kiwi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc5", "question": "Which maritime explorer gave the Pacific Ocean its name?", "answer": "Ferdinand Magellan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b387", "question": "In which country was the first soccer World Cup held?", "answer": "Uruguay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe767aeeec85e375820b294", "question": "Where is the oldest, continuously operating zoo?", "answer": "Vienna, Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab952086faa38a764be512", "question": "What was the first production car to break the 200 mph top speed limit?", "answer": "The Ferrari F40", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca03", "question": "What natural events are ranked in severity by the Saffir Simpson scale?", "answer": "Hurricanes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee5", "question": "The first Tonka truck was made in what year?", "answer": "1947", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a6", "question": "Who produced the radio show \"The War of the Worlds\"?", "answer": "Orson Welles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927f", "question": "In seasons 12 and 13 of the TV show \"Big Brother\", what competitor is associated with \"crybernating\"?", "answer": "Rachel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d72", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Modern Prometheus\"?", "answer": "Frankenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523e56736d4be723796b4e", "question": "In what decade did Toronto surpass Montreal as the most populous city in Canada?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cbd3877e98cb97778a20", "question": "In what U.S. city is South Beach located?", "answer": "Miami Beach, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a161", "question": "Arnold Schwarzenegger is a father trying to get the must have Christmas toy in which 1996 film?", "answer": "Jingle All The Way\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff213af31a458464a93c451", "question": "Pineapples, kiwis and papayas contain enzymes that can do what to meat?", "answer": "Tenderize it", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1f", "question": "What author created Discworld?", "answer": "Terry Pratchett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5cb70cdcf96e155acab35d30", "question": "What country once technically fought a war against a species of bird?", "answer": "Australia, \"The Emu War\"", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f62", "question": "In the children's book \"Feyesper and the Rogue Kite\", what animal is Feyesper based on?", "answer": "Pink fairy armadillo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acdd", "question": "What connection did Thomas Edison have with the construction of Yankee Stadium?", "answer": "His company made the cement", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad87", "question": "Who proposed the idea of \"Laissez-faire\"?", "answer": "Adam Smith", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bd05aedce677f092a9a4018", "question": "In the book \"The Aspen Account\", who is revealed to be dead at the start?", "answer": "Kurt Matthews", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4af", "question": "At what nation does Panama attach onto South America?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbab", "question": "What game introduced the characters Raiden, Liu Kang, and Sub-Zero?", "answer": "Mortal Kombat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921e", "question": "What does the \"L\" stand for in Samuel L. Jackson?", "answer": "Leroy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a52b", "question": "The majority of the Sierra Nevada Mountains are located in which state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ac", "question": "Which country invented the Wankel engine, also known as a rotary engine?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a876", "question": "In what city would you find \"Peachtree Street\"?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa3eb2c73aa70ea0b70af9", "question": "What was an alternative name for Maryland?", "answer": "Mariana (Lord Baltimore squashed the idea because the name reminded him of Spanish Jesuit and historian Juan de Mariana.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d9692596a59cbdfbd3c4", "question": "Who led the covert mission known as the Boston Tea Party?", "answer": "Samuel Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd63", "question": "What Indonesian word names the art of successively waxing and dyeing fabric?", "answer": "Batik", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d6", "question": "What city is located across the Columbia River from the city of Vancouver?", "answer": "Portland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad18", "question": "Which female appeared on the 1999 US dollar coin?", "answer": "Susan B. Anthony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6007813cbd51d85e222ab649", "question": "What quality is associated with peaches in Chinese art?", "answer": "Peaches symbolizing immortality (or the wish for a long and healthy life) are a common symbol in Chinese art.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f2", "question": "Who is the lead guitarist in the band \"The Who\"?", "answer": "Pete Townsend", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe73424eec85e375820b22e", "question": "Who succeeded Al Capone after he went to prison?", "answer": "Paul Ricca and Tony Accardo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c4", "question": "What is the first feature film trilogy to be shot concurrently with the same cast?", "answer": "The Lord of the Rings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388dd", "question": "What mythological beast has the head of a man, the body of a lion, and the tail and feet of a dragon?", "answer": "Manticore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339243", "question": "What is the main character's job in the movie \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "Archeologist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e94827ccba3ffe45786d4", "question": "What year was the Battle of Bannockburn?", "answer": "1314", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65dbc1f3c0ead6880d620", "question": "What did God place at the east of the Garden of Eden after he drove out Adam and Eve?", "answer": "Cherubims", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90e", "question": "What major river runs through Dublin?", "answer": "Liffey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d8", "question": "What was the first man-made satellite put into orbit?", "answer": "Sputnik I", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cdd98e347d002c297e4f2", "question": "Who wrote the collection of short stories on which Fiddler on the Roof was based?", "answer": "Sholem Aleichem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f03", "question": "What author created the character of Mike Hammer?", "answer": "Mickey Spillane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c2b", "question": "Which comic book and issue marked the first appearance of Wonder Woman?", "answer": "All Star Comics #8", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e3", "question": "Chablis is the northernmost district of what French wine region?", "answer": "Burgundy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b7", "question": "A famous misquote of Voltaire describes Canada as simply \"a few acres of\" what?", "answer": "Snow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4a1a49076251badbeaaf", "question": "Who was the first leader of the Republic of Texas?", "answer": "Sam Houston -- He later became one of Texas's first senators and then the state's governor.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b571c2367df192a942e3371", "question": "What is the capital of Togo?", "answer": "Lome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cd40d5a685cf15b733e9892", "question": "Why did the Mongolians fail to invade Japan?", "answer": "Because of a typhoon called \"kamikaze\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba5", "question": "What novel, written by E.B. White, tells the story of an adopted mouse?", "answer": "Stuart Little", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf2", "question": "In what sort of landscape would you find an erg?", "answer": "Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76840eec85e375820b29e", "question": "Which U.S. city is referred to as \"The Hub of the Universe\"?", "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935c", "question": "In what city did the TV show \"Full House\" take place?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339955", "question": "What was Norm\u2019s last name on the TV show \"Cheers\"?", "answer": "Peterson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c537", "question": "What month is the Earth closest to the sun?", "answer": "January", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049bc2cf93664eb10486a1", "question": "What year did Frank Miller publish the comic book series \"300\"?", "answer": "1998", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b336", "question": "In which country was the Rosetta Stone found?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a0", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the sun?", "answer": "Helium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c499", "question": "Which English philosopher believed that people in a state of nature are good?", "answer": "John Locke", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a6", "question": "What nation was led by Alexander the Great?", "answer": "Macedon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa5611c73aa70ea0b70b27", "question": "In which country is May Day the only holiday workers are obliged to be given the day off yet still be paid for it?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389bc", "question": "What nationality was Roald Dahl?", "answer": "Welsh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338acf", "question": "What mythological creature grew two new heads for each one that was cut off?", "answer": "Hydra", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c80b", "question": "Which of the four bases of DNA isn't found in RNA?", "answer": "Thymine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4b3ba06d333868d34d6dc", "question": "In what year did the Korean War end?", "answer": "Although hostilities ended in 1953, there was never a formal peace treaty as of 2020", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e72", "question": "What superteam includes Superman, Batman, Wonder Woman, Flash, Green Lantern, Aquaman and Martian Manhunter?", "answer": "The Justice League of America", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af1", "question": "What sporting competition was the focus of the 2007 film \"Balls of Fury\"?", "answer": "Ping Pong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2f3", "question": "Which famed science fiction author wrote the novelization for the 1966 film, \"Fantastic Voyage\"?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339003", "question": "The novel \"Barnaby Rudge\" is set during which riots?", "answer": "Gordon Riots", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bcb", "question": "The gods Loki, Hel and Frey are from which mythological tradition?", "answer": "Norse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b20f", "question": "Who was assassinated by Leon Czolgosz?", "answer": "William McKinley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60078c480eee65b76b9f2671", "question": "What was the first modern credit card?", "answer": "Diners Club", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d6", "question": "In The Simpsons, when Ned Flanders started his own store, he quit his job as what?", "answer": "Pharmaceuticals salesman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6aa1620565ad31a57c810", "question": "Who was the President Kennedy's Secretary of Defense?", "answer": "Robert McNamara", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdffb161cf6db9ac4808cf4", "question": "Where is the largest natural amphitheater in the U.S.?", "answer": "Los Angeles, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b4", "question": "What type of bird is the Brown Thrasher?", "answer": "Songbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d3b62596a59cbdfbd39d", "question": "What does the Turing Test determine in a computer?", "answer": "If it can think like a human", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e80351de59ea584496fe9c", "question": "Dodie Smith wrote what book that later became a very popular Disney film?", "answer": "The Hundred and One Dalmatians", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b3", "question": "What is the main ingredient of guacamole?", "answer": "Avocados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e8", "question": "What surname for John in \"The Importance of Being Earnest\" did Oscar Wilde take from the seaside town he vacationed at?", "answer": "Worthing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c6ae877e98cb977789be", "question": "Which small French town holds an annual festival celebrating Mexico?", "answer": "Barcelonnette", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba18", "question": "What does the abbreviation NASA stand for?", "answer": "National Aeronautics and Space Administration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071e773745b36be73039e3", "question": "What year saw the release of issue #1 of the \"Revival\" comic book series?", "answer": "2012", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b189", "question": "Who was the 40th President of the United States?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff66cd052a821ff76ae8b14", "question": "What does the color red symbolize in relation to the traditional Christmas color?", "answer": "Red symbolizes the blood of Jesus, which was shed during his crucifixion.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c981", "question": "Amazon river dolphins, also known as pink river dolphins, are also referred to as what?", "answer": "Botos or bufeos", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddb2c6ce05a3942286d8f", "question": "What are the names of the Pac-Man ghost enemies?", "answer": "Plinky, Pinky, Inky and Clyde (AKA Pokey)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd972b223c87fd04dd15e53", "question": "Who was the Egyptian deity of cats?", "answer": "Bastet", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d3d", "question": "The novel \"War & Peace\" takes place during what Era?", "answer": "Napoleonic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be580c25415ba52ed6f0ab8", "question": "Doha is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Qatar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cefc125948005ec986edce4", "question": "Who is the eleventh member of the group LOONA to debut", "answer": "Go Won", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d16", "question": "Which planet is named for the Roman God who was the son of Juno and Jupiter?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d7", "question": "What is the end opposite the nose called on a snowboard?", "answer": "Tail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e8a8962404ad935a7e1a63f", "question": "Which Premier League team's mascot is the Red Devil?", "answer": "Manchester United", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1cd", "question": "Creme de Menthe, fresh cream and what other ingredient are combined to make a Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Creme de Cacao", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc11c0469bb8041d07a079", "question": "What is the name of a popular Italian orange and vanilla flavored liqueur?", "answer": "Tuaca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a6", "question": "In what city do The Simpsons live?", "answer": "Springfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae92b2574a5ce6b56b8231", "question": "Who wrote the 1950s play \"The Rose Tattoo\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "596dfbe79616e6c6d4eba4f0", "question": "What animal can you smell a mile away?", "answer": "The skunk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d0c12596a59cbdfbd380", "question": "Who said, \"Slanderers do not hurt me because they do not hit me\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4e", "question": "What popular detective did Robert Downey Jr. portray in a series of movies?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b082", "question": "What famous woman became known as \"The Lady with the Lamp\" during the Crimean War?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a53", "question": "What is the subtitle of the classic novel \"Uncle Tom's Cabin\"?", "answer": "Life Among the Lowly", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a0", "question": "Who was the star of the 1928 movie \"Steamboat Willie\"?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f93", "question": "What is the name of Alice's pet cat?", "answer": "Dinah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe655bcae7e414034b5aeb9", "question": "Mausoleum is a word derived from what ancient ruler?", "answer": "Mausolus, ruler of the ancient Anatolian kingdom of Caria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b753", "question": "Which company marketed the first digital camera, the DCS-100, in 1991?", "answer": "Kodak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b06be662d71a53650fc8", "question": "The four routes through the Vatican Museums all end at what showstopper?", "answer": "Michelangelo\u2019s Creation of Adam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65efb1f3c0ead6880d632", "question": "Outside which New York building was John Lennon killed?", "answer": "The Dakota Building", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b77de662d71a53651012", "question": "What famous philosopher poet said, \"I awoke this morning with devout thanksgiving for my friends, the old and new\"?", "answer": "Ralph Waldo Emerson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59774356284458f1d7854428", "question": "Who wrote \"East of Eden\"?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e0e006d333868d34d722", "question": "\"An eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth\" is a well-known phrase from what collection of 282 laws?", "answer": "The Code of Hammurabi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c305", "question": "How do pythons give birth?", "answer": "They lay eggs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b8d4ec2b42d4a3561a9efd", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is Darcy Parker\u2019s alias?", "answer": "Darcia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7ea28b24f84e0b9f9ffd0", "question": "What is a figure with eight sides called?", "answer": "Octagon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3233d5bf195a31e15d739f", "question": "What product changed its original name in the US from the \"Soundabout\"?", "answer": "Sony's Walkman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f6", "question": "What Italian scientist discovered methane and invented the first battery?", "answer": "Alessandro Volta", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d07753870e6f05ba600862", "question": "Who composed the title music to TV's \"Inspector Morse\"?", "answer": "Barrington Pheloung", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d0", "question": "By area, what is the smallest of the Great Lakes?", "answer": "Lake Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be96", "question": "What two Hall of Famers had the given names \"Henry Louis\"?", "answer": "Lou Gehrig and Hank Aaron", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69b3920565ad31a57c75d", "question": "What was the largest battleship in World War II?", "answer": "Yamato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339430", "question": "What comedic duo of the 1920s and 1930s were real-life best friends?", "answer": "Laurel & Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339302", "question": "At the beginning of the movie \"A Clockwork Orange\", what type of place are Alex and his friends relax at?", "answer": "The Milk Bar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a1", "question": "What 1997 film featured Clint Eastwood, Gene Hackman, Ed Harris, and E.G. Marshall?", "answer": "Absolute Power", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e9a9febfabb9c85d8a97d", "question": "What is the fear of odors known as?", "answer": "Olfactophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd7", "question": "\"A Christmas Story\" was inspired by the childhood reminiscences of what radio personality?", "answer": "Jean Shepherd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0c0", "question": "Prosophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Progress", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f8", "question": "What animated TV show featured characters that repeatedly said \"Helllloooo Nurse!\"?", "answer": "Animaniacs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4bc649076251badbeac8", "question": "What was U.S. President Woodrow Wilson's reelection campaign slogan in 1916?", "answer": "\"He Kept Us Out of War\" -- Despite the slogan, he asked Congress to declare war in 1917.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c08e", "question": "Which river is dammed by the Hoover Dam?", "answer": "Colorado River", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6b698fb6c85e9e634ff49", "question": "What country's national flower is the Wattle?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8cc5494b094db9158309e", "question": "What was the name of the protagonist in the 2016 film \u201cZootopia\u201d?", "answer": "Judy Hopps", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926a", "question": "What movie follows the ins and outs of Lester Burnham's mid-life crisis?", "answer": "American Beauty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c5", "question": "The term \"black market\" was first used during which war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f5", "question": "Who wrote the song \"Mr Tambourine Man\"?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c540", "question": "Alfred Nobel is credited with the invention of what?", "answer": "Dynamite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be10", "question": "Which one of Strawberry Shortcake's four original toy \"friends\" was a boy?", "answer": "Huckleberry Pie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd9733823c87fd04dd15e57", "question": "How many states were in the original US Confederacy?", "answer": "7", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4cd", "question": "What was the first man-made object to leave the Solar System?", "answer": "Voyager 1", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c92e", "question": "Where in the body would you find the malleus, incus and stapes?", "answer": "Ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd821ffd0de9af39e9d46a7", "question": "What was the first species of animal sent to space?", "answer": "Fruit Fly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c8c", "question": "What art word is derived from the French word meaning \"pasting\"?", "answer": "Collage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0d", "question": "What novel won Alice Walker a Pulitzer Prize in 1983?", "answer": "The Color Purple", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b5", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Pakistan and Bangladesh?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae19", "question": "In which decade did Hawaii become a state?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9fd", "question": "What did Gene Siskel and Roger Ebert do for a living?", "answer": "They were movie critics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd86fec223966ae8f88dc", "question": "What actor\u2019s face inspired \"Halloween\" baddie Michael Myers\u2019 mask?", "answer": "William Shatner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b716", "question": "What is the Christmas dinner of choice for families in Burgundy, France?", "answer": "Turkey and chestnuts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cace", "question": "What is heliology the study of?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76685eec85e375820b282", "question": "What is the Japanese word for \"dog\"?", "answer": "Inu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a973", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Bundestag?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a73c", "question": "What US city is home to the Gateway Arch?", "answer": "St. Louis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde51e6c6c6b019850c9a92", "question": "In what nation were the Dead Sea Scrolls found?", "answer": "Jordan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93d576bd93ce3a4e5f6b4", "question": "What type of rock is formed by consolidation of molten magma?", "answer": "Igneous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d3", "question": "Canada is divided into provinces and what else?", "answer": "Territories", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ea", "question": "Which Hollywood film studio's logo is a mountain surrounded by 22 stars?", "answer": "Paramount", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9bb03364247bf200fb89e", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Trafalgar\"?", "answer": "The Bee Gees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c1", "question": "Coq au vin is a dish made with which type of meat?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b077", "question": "What was the last name of Civil Rights activist Malcolm X?", "answer": "Little", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a763", "question": "In which US state does the Rio Grande river begin?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81c", "question": "What color blazer is presented to the Masters golf winner?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b36df71c3f17ccc40c8e07", "question": "Who wrote and directed the 1999 film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "M. Night Shyamalan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a075", "question": "Who was the first woman to appear naked on the front cover of \"Radio Times\"?", "answer": "Helen Mirren", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5b6e5dad637d903c881a", "question": "What luxury fashion house funded the restoration of Rome's Trevi Fountain?", "answer": "Fendi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a831", "question": "The powerful Inca empire had its capital seat at Cuzco in what modern-day South American country?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a817", "question": "What city is the fashion center of Italy?", "answer": "Milan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c6749076251badbead3", "question": "In the U.S., the 1920s were often described by what term?", "answer": "The roaring twenties ", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121a9563c99d48cd169b04", "question": "What is the common name for enuresis?", "answer": "Bedwetting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe523531bf59ab7d2e380ef", "question": "Swarovski is associated with what product?", "answer": "Chrystal jewelry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7facff048f679a45ac14", "question": "What poison is found in apple seeds?", "answer": "Cyanide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65d3e1f3c0ead6880d619", "question": "What Enron CEO took the company to financial disaster?", "answer": "Kenneth Lay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e942c7ccba3ffe45786cf", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Californium?", "answer": "Cf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c847fbde8045e48466d5", "question": "What kind of unique fur does a platypus have?", "answer": "As if it weren't an odd enough creature, the platypus' fur is bioluminescent, meaning they can glow in the dark.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a7", "question": "What important crop is the Rhine Valley in Germany known for growing?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac5", "question": "What quality does a \"rhopalic\" sentence have?", "answer": "Each word has one more letter or syllable than the previous word", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3d6cff048f679a45ab4d", "question": "From which language does the name \"coyote\" originate?", "answer": "Aztec", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339505", "question": "Iron Man's suit is powered by a reactor located where?", "answer": "In his chest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab41", "question": "What is the official language of Austria?", "answer": "German", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d90", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Shad Moss?", "answer": "Bow Wow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cb7e877e98cb97778a1c", "question": "Which country's Easter brunch typically includes a ryemeal soup known as zurek?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6fc", "question": "How many wheels does a pair of roller skates have?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}]